[
    {
        "question": ".............. of the tractors manufactured world- wide is produced in India.",
        "options": [
            "One fifth",
            "One tenth",
            "One fourth",
            "One third"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The ............... industry are labour intensive.",
        "options": [
            "Silk",
            "Handloom",
            "Cement",
            "Jute"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "By the end of 1972, ............... small industries were registered with the government.",
        "options": [
            "4 lakh 16 thousand",
            "3 lakh 16 thousand",
            "4 lakh 18thousand",
            "3 lakh 18 thousand"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Textile Committee was established in .............. .",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1948",
            "1954",
            "1970"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Industrial Licensing Policy of ............... all those factories requiring investment of more than5 crore to be included as heavy industries.",
        "options": [
            "1954",
            "1963",
            "1975",
            "1970"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The task of conservation of the forests is done by the central government, the state government and by the............... .",
        "options": [
            "Private banks",
            "Local people",
            "Industries",
            "Public sector"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The research annual production of salt in India is .............. lakh tons.",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "300",
            "600",
            "400"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "How much % does gems and jewellery contribute to India’s Exports?",
        "options": [
            "12%",
            "25%",
            "13%",
            "7%"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "The Automobile industry is called the .............. sector in India.",
        "options": [
            "Sunrise",
            "Sunset",
            "Emerging",
            "Export"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Vehicles are exported to .............. Countries from India.",
        "options": [
            "50",
            "40",
            "30",
            "20"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The main centre of bicycle manufacturing in India is Ludhiana.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Modern techniques like ............... and organic farming are used for farming.",
        "options": [
            "Ploughing",
            "Drip irrigation",
            "Threshing",
            "Harvesting"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "How much % does Agriculture contribute to India’s Exports?",
        "options": [
            "3%",
            "5%",
            "10%",
            "7%"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "'Mega Cluster' is a scheme that helps .............. through self-finance groups and non-governmentalorganisations.",
        "options": [
            "Farmers",
            "People",
            "Weavers",
            "Sculptors"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Industrial Finance Corporation of India was established in .............. .",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1948",
            "1954",
            "1970"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The textile industry forms .............. of the total industrial production.",
        "options": [
            "14%",
            "17%",
            "12%",
            "16%"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Industrial Development Corporation of India was established in .............. .",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1948",
            "1954",
            "1970"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    }
]